I have your briefcase of 20!
Air raid alarm came home so easily.
He started, however.
Do you know what that means?
Man, or what were you?
To phone? Do you have anything for the post office?
Herr Schultz?  Thank you.
What is that, thank you, an American?  Yes. I got them in Spain.
Department please.  Did you come from Spain?
He is on the list, whether to be picked up from Mansfeld to Rome and probably in the Vatican again?
Thank goodness that you are here. Come in right now, you are urgently needed.  Gimpel is here.
From now on hold all meetings.
Hello! I stayed in the sunny south, I stayed there a bit longer.  Why do I think you want something from me? What's happening?
You should win the war. I am late. What is it? The most secret commando thing of the war.
But here in the office everyone knows. I, in your place, stayed in Spain. know in your place, who remained in Spain. Makes me curious.
See you later?
Yes, we'll have a Cognac later.
Hello Inge!  Erich! Please don't. What do I do? Who were you hoping for?
Are not you glad that I came?
But I brought you something. Parisian perfume.
That's it. In Madrid we meet tonight.
If you're still here afterwards. Mr. Gimpel is here.
I did not know that- I'll come you later.  No, they're all here because of you. What, for my sake? Yes. Please get us a Cognac, Shäfer. Yes sir.
Are you tired? A little bit already.
But now I'm really curious.
Can you be too?
You know Gimpel that we have another job for you. Thank you.
They have imagination, are intelligent and have great courage.
As if you wanted to give me a medal.
Medal?
No.
This means that we will give you the order.
Is something like a medal. Do you know what that is?
That was natural.
I do not know how far I can expect physical knowledge.
Let's wait for it. What is the German about?
Professor Hahn managed to split uranium before the war and thus to release atomic nuclei.
Hahn's research came to America.
The Americans immediately recognized that if Germany continued to do so, it would very soon be able to use nuclear energy for military purposes.
For a bomb, you understand, an atomic bomb.
And so America immediately began to undertake the production of such a bomb.
And that's just it.
We do not know it. We know a lot.
This is called the Manhattan Project.
We can say names here, addresses of people they can use to approach the project.
What do you mean? Approaching passing.
United States?
Yes, you are our best man.
We have no other choice.
Listen, we have no choice.
Let's tell you what it means to have the atomic bomb.
Whoever has them first wins them.
No matter where we stand, whether at the urn or in the Caucasus, it does not matter what happens when you throw an atomic bomb.
It's hard to believe but an atomic bomb has the power of millions of tons of dynamite.
What is happening? Total annihilation within a radius of several kilometers by a flash of light, in the core 6000 degrees Celsius prevail.
Then comes a blast of pressure, which causes every house to collapse and ruptures unhinged people's skin.
If she has not been burned before.
And not to forget the radioactivity itself!
That's enough. That's why we brought her here.
We need to know how far the Americans are, not just how far they are, but everything they can find out.
Every little thing is important.
We need technical details, drawing and construction plans, where we built the bomb like the works to each other.
Where are the sensitive, the vulnerable points?
How can you paralyze the production?
And all as an assignment to a single man, a single man?
How do you communicate with the whole order?
You're the first person we're referring to, as a scout here or from South America, so to speak.
There is a whole organization waiting there, just for you and with whom you are in constant contact.
What is the cause? There's a message in American newspapers Which newspaper?
La Prensa? They get you, all over America, the messages worked out.
This is all very well and nice, but that the whole plan as such at all a chance, the chance they have, may not be great.
But we also have to take the smallest chance.
Probably we have to succeed, but maybe it will not be enough for me.
Excuse me but conquers the electric chair.
I prefer to take pictures. That's why it's an assignment that you want to volunteer.
How should I get over?
There is a possibility with a specially equipped woman.
You would have to parachute back to America back and forth.
So much fuel does not have you back.
Could not it be an insane company with a freighter?
That's not a problem. You have to arrive from South America.
At the corner you know me.
I find the most promising the crossing with a U-Boat.
Two men get that.
You want a whole fleet, you can have.
The American coast is the best guarded in the world.
At New York, there are only two or three bays that are suitable.
The Americans know that.
I thought of the French.
Sommerfeldt.
And fear does not do that.
I'll wonder I'll be fine.
Let's say the landing works, although the chance is one in a hundred.
What do I do then? There are far too many ways to attract attention.
Let us not fool ourselves, gentlemen.
A European smells one.
These are not reasons. We get everything we need.
I want to tell you what I need.
A man who goes along.
There have to be Americans.
A genuine. I have never been to New York.
I need someone who can tell me how to get from the train station, how to get my hair cut, how far you wear your pants, how to take a cigarette out with your fingers, need an average guy somewhere, tell me all about it and on which I can rely.
Can you have it? I will then notify abroad.
That's not a good idea. There we certainly find no problem.
Act as if you only had how important.
You get what you need dollars.
50,000 hundreds of thousands, gold or diamonds?
Say yes.
Advances.
I have the feeling that when I jasper, I put the rope around my neck myself.
Nobody wants to lie to us.
But it's the job that's ever been forgiven.
Gimpel.
Go to America!
They are arrested. I can die.
Such an assignment would only be awarded to the world once.
Do not you understand that this irritates a man, just has to irritate him?
Besides, you want to throw that atomic bombs are bad enough.
Eight men were then transferred to America, also with U-Boats.
That's when we knew they were coming.
They landed on the electric chair.
But you did not see the files.
Did we collect everything? Seeing files and photos of what a human being looks like, who is chasing electrical current through his body.
A pretty picture.
I've been watching the defense for four years now.
Do not you think about it yet? Dirty business is the dirty business.
Since you would be at 20 meters, the bay is secured, probably by a destroyer, of course, by radar and home appliances.
That is, 90 percent of the risk of premature discovery exists.
Of course you have to be lucky.
I mean, why should not you be lucky?
Your honest opinion?
Asked for his honest opinion.
I want to know you. The whole thing is a suicide mission, as it is written in the book.
The Americans have really found one.
Exactly the right thing. I have to look at it.
Real Americans become German father and he hates America.
Why do you hate America?
Why does the story tell about your father?
He was interned. I finished it.
I mean, he died there, and since then hates America.
He is great, the very man we were looking for.
He was born in Boston, older than him.
Can not be, and why he tells here has deserted, defected.
He just has too much anger on America.
We can do whatever they want.
Against the.
Do you like it well?
He does not wear too much, do not worry.
Incidentally, the suitcases came as they wanted.
He looks like an American suitcase, did we say everything?
What are they real?
From department store in Boston has a double bottom, there comes in the radio.
The new one is the most modern shortwave transmitter we have.
Good.
What are not you doing?
I do not know why, I can not say it, but at some point you stand there and do not know what you're doing in.
I am very glad that I like to do something as you are.
What you do, you only do out of vanity.
I do not know what you are going to do about the United States now.
You say you love me.
You're kidding yourself. You can not live.
Then nothing. You do not know for love.
Maybe you can say that's just too easy.
The place where we will end up, when all goes well.
Career changers.
Cheered.
Ending the day with the fresh air.
For how much longer?
You will not believe it, but I'm looking forward to it.
I can be eaten any moment, can the captain?
Is there a reasonable suspicion that companies betray themselves in their free choice at their own discretion?
What does that mean?
Two days was traveling 46 days.
It must be there because of the suspicion.
Discretion.
I am driven for it. It remains to learn.
Yes, pretty close to running water depths the traffic on the road very strong.
20. A destroyer is running.
He comes right to us.
Now and then taxes.
Targeted.
On Seehofer everything is fine, he runs off.
I understand very well, do you understand?
Gets away.
And then I followed the trail.
What do you mean, what kind of people came from the water?
Of course I have read before.
I saw her, too. Two men with heavy weapons and radios.
Yes, probably a fantasy.
What I say Our guys over there are on the Rhine, and we have other concerns than sending spies.
Take a taxi and ten minutes?
That's exactly the way to the court martial.
They would not hang.
Why should not I say, because I know what's going on.
If it calms you, we would hang side by side.
Just the feeling that I could call home.
Maybe my mother is on the phone.
I do not need to say anything.
That will not do. But I know it can not be.
From a dead son his mother has nothing.
Dallas.
What is going on, what is going on now Dollars with banderole of the German Reichsbank these damned idiots?
It's my own fault. I should have taken care.
Stay away. That's at least 50,000 50,000.
What's this?
The real?
I do not have a dollar leather bag.
000 dollars Reicherts.
You have to get together! Not a word too much, think of the gallows, you are standing down.
Exactly 300,000.
I feel like you still have not got what's going on and how dangerous everything is.
We belong Together. Everyone alone is lost, never had so much money in life at one go.
None of us can let the others down.
Why, I know. I do not want to hang.
Now with 1000 dollars in the bag.
Let's sleep now, and tomorrow morning we'll be in New York.
The.
What do you do?
In the evening in a lonely place on the coast Two men see carrying heavy suitcases.
I would look very carefully, if you see far and wide nothing.
Nothing went to the police We laughed at him.
That's how German agents have gone ashore.
The war is over for a couple of damn weeks off.
There are still such insane people in our crazy business.
When I think about it, we have two cunning and dangerous agents in the States, maybe even in the middle.
I hope you'll take the saying that there's something going on.
I do not remember when he has set up the apparatus.
I feel so funny. It does not work so fast.
What are you saying? I feel like being in a mousetrap.
Do we always have to stay in this room?
Yes, it is better. I do not know if I should do something different.
And I want to tell you what you mean.
We should take the money and cheer.
But I say so too.
You, you say.
In the cinema there. Reading with this newspaper.
We have two connections with our people here, the advertisements in the newspaper.
Is an address that I am visiting now.
It starts, the apparatus stays in the room until I come back.
Can someone hear us here? No.
I do not know who they are.
I did not steal my time.
Why is?
At 58 000 634 dollars and 40 cents.
In the years 38 to 42 have received from the German secret service?
That is not true.
I do not know what you're talking about, you have to be crazy.
Can you see it? Where are you from?
I come from berlin. Berlin.
That's a joke! Listen, I have as little time as you.
I have been given a lot of documentation in case your memory should fail them.
They got a lot of dollars for a lot of information that was not bad.
I want to expressly confirm you, if that is your fault, and.
What do you want from me? You have to help me.
Out of business.
You now have a good going on the money of the German defense.
Do you have the business too?
The family does not mind ruining me, making me unhappy?
No, and please stay away from the desk.
If you think of calling the FBI to let me go, remember that you would go up with it.
What do you want from me?
I would like to make you an offer.
I learn from you how I approach the project, the atomic bomb.
You know? Of course I know.
Is that not allowed again?
That helps you something else?
That's not my thing. An agent no longer fulfills orders.
I'll get some addresses from you that will help me when I get them.
Then they will never see me again.
But may I give you some advice?
If I were you, I'd run away to South America as fast as I can.
Best I do not like the climate.
The climate is worse.
In three days I will be the address.
I'll be back soon.
I can not say he will eventually and then you stand there and do not know what to do.
She is on the phone because someone is there.
You're an idiot!
If my life is dear to me and it is mine, you are killing us, if I am today, then tomorrow, then it is better if I suddenly.
What kind of idiot are you?
Do I sleep?
I do not have it yet.
What can you drink here? Listen to.
You will understand. I have no desire to be seen with them.
In it you will find an address with which you meet, exactly what you produce.
How can I reach him? And now do not tell me goodbye!
I have everything.
Pull the bill, pay for the suitcase.
You have to give me a little chance.
He has to leave the suitcases somewhere.
A small chance. A very small one.
I have my money two suitcases.
I have not lost, you would have my bags there, they stand.
Here are always a lot of trouble, I'm not all that annoying.
Exactly what?
What is inside?
A pajamas, striped black and yellow, then a camera, a Leica.
Two ties, one gray, one black blue striped.
This is an electronic radio operator.
Do you meet old acquaintances again?
Not for six years. At that time we had together, we are now relatives.
Do you still remember his daughter?
Did they deport you then?
Did they first intern me and then let them go?
Yes, I have here.
I want to leave again.
But we have to see each other What do you live?
I can help you there. Besides, we do not know that again through the rags.
Here are the keys when one is called.
I am still not married.
I do not get along.
I have to be honest, I'm looking forward to it.
Goodbye! Goodbye!
I do not understand either.
That can only, what was in it.
Or maybe you found?
I gave up myself.
I think it's alright that a friend of mine.
What are you doing here? I wanted to ask you the same.
I am a friend of Paulo Santé, left me his apartment.
He has to have several keys and a lot of people to whom he confides.
Apparently, they've known him pretty well for a long time.
We were together in Peru before the war, at the same company.
Today I met him again.
I have a small fashion store, it is being refurbished.
I always said he gave me the keys.
Of course I leave you the apartment.
I can sleep in the business as well.
I have me too.
They are not Americans.
Not? Do you notice that?
Yes, I came here via England, for the first time in New York.
Right, I am a deserter from Koln.
We have a whole resume here a gap.
What did you do last year?
I went to Argentina.
Everything came.
My father was here only because he was not operated on time.
Are you saying that you did not want to fight for a country that your father imprisons?
That's why I went to Argentina.
Argentina made.
Addresses.
Tell us, what did you do in New York?
I had just arrived and wanted.
I gave that up.
On road.
Two men, two suitcases.
I hope they realize that desertion costs them a lot.
Two men and two suitcases.
I ask you Say, how did you come to the States?
Why do you answer? I do not know.
You do not know that? But I know you have to think about why.
At what time of the day, with which train did you just come by train?
With which, you say?
Answer, where did you go ashore?
That's what I asked, when, where do you answer Can not you come with a German U-Boat?
I do not know, what do you want?
I want to tell you what it was like.
It was almost midnight, a bit foggy on the road, on the coast, traffic, lights.
They came ashore on a dinghy.
Gerudert were German marines.
There was someone with them.
They had two suitcases.
They went out into the woods through the woods, stopped a car!
Why do not you say?
We have people in Argentina.
I just need a radio message Knowing everything they did.
I flick through every step they have made.
If I know tomorrow morning.
My wife and I are not coming home today, tastes like never before in my life, I do not cook that well again.
Not the food, to be alone with two.
Help me!
Somehow it is strange We only met today and eat together and dream to fall away.
Old couple.
I like it very much.
Unfortunately not always, but it is so rare.
Are you saying that I do not have a boyfriend?
It's safe. Yes and no.
He is straightforward.
I like people who were as easy as he was.
I only love them when they want.
I prefer to stay here.
Why are you smiling because that's so unlikely?
Being here for the first time in a long time is a gift that I do not know if I can accept.
You can always have such gifts.
It's a crazy world.
That's what makes the war confuse me.
I take off the water.
I'll take the bedroom, they'll take this one, that's fine!
We do not need fear for each other.
Erich Gimpel, can you describe what properties it has?
You have to know. Do you have your memory?
We did not let you say everything you know.- Untranslated subtitle -
Leaving a name of a special kind to go somewhere to move.
American, what a special you were before.
But now you are an agent who has made an attack on the United States.
We have no reason to understand it.
They will have squeezed them out like a lemon.
What do you know about that?
Have a land gone without a purpose?
I swear, I do not know.
I'm still talking to you.
But at some point he visited someone, he did not tell me.
Once he said there should be more, even more people, maybe the South American newspaper.
I think we are on the trail of a big deal.
I still know something.
He always picks up the money up here.
Excelsior. I got her name from.
When and where can we see each other?
How do I recognize it?
I have understood. A dog.
I help you with me were 2.
I hope that will.
That's about as accurate as a photograph.
All the powers that we need authority, as we have never owned it, is arranged like surveillance.
Just as important are the time circumstances, thousands of people would have to use it to pay for them.
When a man comes and asks for a South American newspaper, he pays cash.
And what about the press?
Not a word of that the public ever put on a man.
He has to be found.
14 million people.
And what about dogs?
I am still very young.
Do we want to talk here? Why not?
Do not run away! Sad!
You know what it's about. They want to know what they understand.
I am interested in details that I can get.
Technically, militarily, politically.
And what is this worth to you?
The interests are different.
Some want to win wars.
If you ask me I want to buy a farm.
I find that fun. 00:00 At first, you can be sure of being talked to.
More. If I find out anything, nothing to say against.
And why did you say?
You do not need to retell.
It is too little for that.
There you have to go on a leash.
He gets it done and the United States leg.
Are you talking to a scientist now?
I can not tell you the name, but great class, I'll let you know.
And do not forget that I still need a lot of money.
That's Washington again.
I know what you want.
Who duplicates this immediately?
Any cop in New York apparently can not believe it, then we can wrap up.
They pretend that not a man has landed, but a whole army.
Somewhere, somewhere in this damned sea of houses.
Since I have the business, I feel happy, understanding.
Somehow I'm proud that I made it.
Later I still have the incidental business.
I've already talked to the people here on the first floor.
Of course that will be a kind of music of the future for a long time to come.
But I have already finished the plans.
Do you think that's so far ahead of you?
No not at all.
Sure, you know what you want.
A future? It's not questionable.
All we have to do is buy something.
We are eating at home again.
You do not believe how fun I am.
I mean cooking and caring for someone.
Looks like I want to catch a guy.
So far, there was not one that I would have liked.
I was more intentional for myself.
What can I say?
Anything?
I have to do something good now.
I once had a girlfriend.
I have a lot of friends then.
What about the girlfriend?
She once told me you do not love anyone.
But maybe you'll learn it someday, sometime, probably when you need it.
Now it is time.
Tell me, why if you?
Well, I've already noticed.
There is something with you.
You are restless, you are smoking all the time.
You are so nervous. Why restless?
I do not have anything. Not really.
You have no position. Not completely honest right now.
Do you need money? Yes, I understand myself correctly.
I would like to help you.
I really do not need money.
Erik is never so important.
Do you think I will think about it?
Where did I meet this professor?
He sits on a bench and reads his newspaper.
Next to him is a black leather briefcase.
They ask if there is still a place left.
And he says please. He then puts the briefcase from one side to the other.
Good.
Another question. I would like to have an overview of a map Do you understand how the works relate to each other and what is produced in them?
I understand when I get that.
Are you a step closer to your farm?
I would like to hear more about that.
I only get a newspaper.
They seem to understand something.
I have a home myself, broken all carpets.
You should! You can see my wife, my wife.
Do not we mind?
I suppose you do not call him.
That's one thing, it does.
You maybe not enough.
But I have nothing to do with your money.
Understand, I do not want it.
People who work their money are always.
I prefer the others because they have better motives.
However, we do not really want to go anywhere else.
They do not know where I work.
Within concrete blocks silent goes through automatically.
No one has replaced television for a long time.
It does not matter.
We see the meaning of life.
You want to know technical details.
Why are you meeting me then?
There are no more technical difficulties.
It does not take more years.
It is a proof to construct this bomb.
Do you know what I want now?
Do you understand atomic bombs?
I understand everything, but a few thousand people here in New York are busy with nothing else.
Including me if they accept that.
We can not use radio and press, because we are pure coincidence, depending on some stupid.
There is no hotel where I am our people.
May I help you! I have.
With 69?
We do not even have one.
Browse almost every room.
Have you run? You are not dressed.
Please do not make me angry.
Good, I'm here, but my divorce is already running.
We also want to marry what we want.
But Casanova could have gone awry too.
Shall not let me stop.
Is there a home search somewhere?
What happened then?
Please give me only water, it must not be.
But what happened?
Please do not ask, I can not answer you.
I have everything continuously day and night.
But maybe I already lost you.
Now, at that moment, because I can not say why I was where I was, I was looking for the police.
I do not get it. We have not known each other for a long time, but we do not know each other like a criminal.
It's not you.
You want to say, I do not need to explain you.
It's crazy. I have not had many goals in this life, I mean.
I had the goods wrong.
Now I see it. I have it all.
That's the best thing I've ever had.
John. And that includes everything happiness.
Suddenly everything gets.
I still have everything in my hand.
I can put an end to everything I've done so far.
You said it is fine in my opinion, if it is at my discretion.
So now I can finish with everything.
I stop. Would you go to South America with me?
Yes, I worked there.
I can start right now.
A life with you. If you want.
I am tomorrow, we lead everything in the way.
You can sell or rent the store.
I get the tickets.
Life is a nice thing.
After 30 hours we are in Rio.
Oh please, airport, I'll get a newspaper, I'll be right back.
You're under arrest. You are Gimpel.
I am glad that he caught you, you lasted longer than your predecessors.
They smoke, what drink.
Take it as an expression of my appreciation for this achievement. After all, you have kept a few thousand people in suspense, not to mention panting.
But did you actually do this madness?
I know I could now make his hero out of me and say I do that for my country, what you do for your country.
But. I do not say it.
You caught me Enjoy your triumph?
Defendant Gimpel As chairman of this commission, I have the duty to inform you of the verdict that was passed on them.
You are found guilty on all counts and sentenced to death by hanging.
They should eat something when they starve.
I forget How long do I have to live?
Everyone always asks the same thing.
I do not know, but only twelve hours before.
That's the rule.
I'm here for three weeks now.
I know that the verdict in four weeks, after a week.
The cook will be annoyed if you send the food back.
He asked extra what you like.
Why wants to do a favor?
Tomorrow, not the day after tomorrow.
If you do not betray me. I have the suffering of 15 April in 4.
What is it, what?
What will you do? You should not build on this reputation.
There are other farms, they would not hear anything.
But I have nothing to say.
You do not hear me, that it has to happen someday.
That is nothing new.
But there is also something pretty.
You will be glad you have a visit when visiting a woman.
Come. You know it's forbidden.
I can not be annoying now.
Not allowed. Until I got the permission.
Good that you did not come too late.
I am very glad that I still see you.
Is there nothing left to do, is there no hope?
The petition for mercy is. They refused.
I dont say anything. Everything that I have to say, I have already told myself.
I am so sorry. We should not have met, because.
The luck to see or to suspect, that is too little.
The very thought of having it, almost having it.
This thought drives me crazy.
Eric. I'm still trying to do something.
Another pardon or something?
It's war. You have to hang me.
You just have to. If the war was over tomorrow they might pardon me, but it will not be a few weeks longer for me, a few weeks too long.
And that little bit is missing.
That's my death. Let's not talk about it!
I'm so glad you came.
The time is.
When the time comes, you have to go.
And thank you.
Tell me, have you been lucky in your life?
Yes, pretty much.
But in the end, I am here.
I stood.
What does that mean for me? Probably that you live.
Four, because no one is executed during this time.
Understand these are the weeks you are missing.
You will be pardoned for life.
That means again sometime you let them run.
Maybe in ten years.
Sometime.